PROFILE

I'm a software engineer based in Shanghai China, specializing in developing and monitoring exceptional, high-quality websites, web applications, and Wechat Mini Programs. I have 3+ years of experience as a software engineer. Team Lead, and Project manager. mostly working using JavaScript and its major framework and libraries. mostly of my work is frontend related which is based on Single page applications, analytics dashboard, Data visualization, Progressive web application and Wechat mini programs' have strong knowledge of backend development and i have worked on database design, REST and SOAP architectures API for Web applications, mobile applications, Blockchain and IOT based projects.

CONTACT

Wechat Marahman49

Phone 18621549424 0345-2684189

EMAIL:

marahmanis@gmail.com

HOBBIES

- Programming
- Reading
- Running
- Hiking

Muhammad Anis Ur Rahman

Software Engineer

EDUCATION

BS Software Engineer

University Of Swat (Pakistan)

2013 - 2017

BS Software Engineering (BSSE) degree to fulfil the need of the growing software market. The program has been designed to produce professionals who have excellent problem solving skills and can solve complex computational problems by critically thinking and analysing the problems. The curriculum provides well-adjusted mix of basic science, technology, linguistics and business related areas to produce graduate capable of holding leadership position both in research and non-academic sectors.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

Livecom Shanghai (China) December 2019– Current

- Product Development.
- API Integration.
- Dashboard Development
- Unit/integration Testing.
- Wechat Mini Programs
- Chat Integration

Software Engineer

ShareIN Shanghai (China) November 2018– December 2019

- Product Development.
- API development and Integration.
- Progressive web applications.
- Unit/integration Testing.
- Algorithm Implementation.
- Payment Gateways Like Alipay Wechat Pay
- Wechat Mini Programs

Software Engineer

Freshchefs Shanghai (China) Apr 2018– October 2018

- Web Application Development.
- Food delivery system development.
- Reservation Integration.
- Wechat Mini Programs

LANGUAGES

- English
- Pashto
- Urdu
- Chinese

INTREST

- Blockchain
- Python
- Data Science
- A

Stack overflow

LinkedIn

<u>Github</u>

Software Engineer (Intern)

Lahore (Pakistan) Aug 2017– March 2018

- Document and test new software applications.
- Assess new application ideas.
- Research competitor offerings.
- Develop applications (coding, programming)
- Interview beta testers.

SKILLS

Mostly focused on web development and hybrid mobile application development have given me a perfect grip on most of JavaScript frameworks. following are my key skills:

- HTML5/WXML
- CSS3/WXSS/SCSS
- Bootstrap 3/4 / Material design/ UI Kit
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Angular 1.x
- Vue JS/Vuex/Nuxt/Vue-router
- React JS/Redux
- Vuetify/Quasar
- Node JS
- Express/Koa/Sails/Loopback
- Web Sockets
- Webpack's
- MongoDB/Mongoose
- MYSQL
- Wechat Mini Programs

PROJECTS

Please visit my Career Portfolio to check my latest work